This is the part where we start putting everything together.
这部分课程中 我们开始把所有工作放到一起
Bear with me a bit on this video because there is a lot to show.
这个视频请稍微坚持一下 因为有很多东西需要展示
Here's a reminder of where we are so far.
回顾一下目前为止的情况
I have this web app with roots and HTML templates,
我拥有这个带有路由和 HTML 模板的 Web 应用
but the templates aren't particularly interesting yet.
但模板还不够有趣
There's also a CSV file that's imported and wrangled with pandas.
还有一个用 pandas 导入和整理的 CSV 文件
This is the file that does all the wrangling.
这是进行整理工作的文件
The goal is to take this wrangled data,
目标是使用这些整理后的数据
setup a plotly visualization and show the visualization on the front-end.
设置 plotly 可视化并在前端显示
Let's look at the routes.py file.
来看一下 routes.py 文件
My wrangling data dashboard was actually only one webpage so I only need one route.
我的数据仪表板实际上只有一个网页 所以我只需要一个路由
I'm going to erase this second route down here.
我要删除第二个路由
I've got all this data here in this data variable.
这个 data 变量中获取了所有数据
Let's start the web app just so we can see what that data looks like.
启动 Web 应用 方便我们查看数据的样式
The data is getting printed out in the routes file.
routes 文件打印出了 data 数据
It's a list of tuples where each tuple contains a country name,
这是一个元组列表 其中每个元组都包含一个国家名称、
X values and Y values.
x 值和 y 值
So how can we convert this into a visualization?
那么如何将其转换为可视化?
You need to somehow send this data which is sitting on
你需要以某种方式将这些数据
the back-end and get it over to the front-end. How can you do that?
从后端发送到前端 怎样做到呢?
In the render template method,
在 render_template 方法中
you can actually send variables to the front-end.
实际上可以将变量发送到前端
All you have to do is list them after you specify the template name.
只需在指定模板名称后列出即可
That's what I've done here by saying, ''data_set = data.''
这就是我在这里所写的 data_set = data
Now the front-end is going to have access to this data set variable.
现在前端可以访问这个 data_set 变量
Let's switch over to the index.html front-end code.
切换到 index.html 前端代码
This index.html just has regular HTML in it,
index.html 中只有常规的 HTML
but Flask actually includes a template engine called Ginger.
但 Flask 实际上包含一个名为 Jinja 的模板引擎
A template engine is a tool that lets you reuse HTML by introducing variables.
模板引擎是一种工具 可以通过引入变量 让你复用 HTML
Here's what I mean: the data set
详细解释一下
variable from the back-end is now available to the front-end.
从后端传来的 data_set 变量 现在前端也可以访问了
All you have to do is wrap the variable name in curly braces like this.
你要做的就是将变量名称包装在这样的大括号中
Now let's go to the front end.
现在打开前端
On the index.html page all of the data is just now being printed out,
在 index.html 页面上 所有数据现在都打印出来了
so we were able to get the data from the back-end and show it on the front-end.
所以我们能够从后端获取数据并在前端显示
In fact with Ginger,
实际上 使用 Jinja
you can write control flow statements like if and for.
你可以编写控制流语句 如 if 和 for
This can give you more control over the formatting,
这可以更好地控制格式
you just have to learn the syntax. Let me show you.
你只需要学习语法 我先来演示一下
Going back to index.html I'm going to write a fore loop.
回到 index.html 我要写一个 for 循环
Let's see what this fore loop looks like on the front-end.
看看这个 for 循环在前端如何表现
So it's iterating through all of the data and printing it out line by line.
它会遍历所有数据并逐行打印
You could imagine using this syntax maybe to make a table for the data for example.
你可以想象 使用这种语法可能能用数据制作一个表格
The syntax is that variables are surrounded by
语法是 变量用两个大括号括起来
two squiggly brackets and control statements
控制语句是一个大括号和一个百分号
The reason why these variables and control statements
之所以需要以某种方式将这些变量和控制语句区分开
the template engine knows what part is actually
是为了使模板引擎知道哪部分实际上
HTML tags and what part is a variable or a control statement.
是 HTML 标签 哪部分是变量或控制语句
You can imagine why this is called a template engine.
你可以想象为什么这会被叫做模板引擎
The HTML can be re-used as a skeleton and the information in the variables might change.
HTML 可以作为骨架复用 变量中的信息可能会发生变化
So the next step is to figure out how to set up a plotly visualization
下一步是弄清楚如何在 Python 后端设置 plotly 可视化
in the Python back-end and then send this information to the front-end.
然后将可视化信息发送到前端